acumatica.com 2018-12-25

# Privacy Policy | Acumatica Cloud ERP

**Last Updated May 22, 2018**

Your privacy is important to us. To better protect your privacy we provide this notice explaining our online information practices.  Please read this privacy statement closely.  You accept the terms of this private statement by continuing to use Acumatica’s products and services.

**Policy**

Acumatica, Inc., a Delaware corporation (“Acumatica”) will never sell, rent, barter, trade, distribute or lease personal information to outside parties unless Acumatica obtains customer permission or disclosure is required by law.

**Purpose**

** ** Acumatica uses the information customers provide only to the extent necessary to offer our services to our customers. Acumatica believes in both minimizing the data that is collected and limiting its use and purpose to only that: 1) for which we have been given permission by customers, 2) as necessary to deliver our services, and 3) as we might be required or permitted for legal, compliance or other lawful purposes.

The only individually identifiable information that Acumatica collects about you is that which you choose to share with us in registration, such as your name, billing address, email address, phone, usernames and passwords. This information will be closely protected and used for internal purposes only. Acumatica uses return email addresses to answer the email Acumatica receives. Such addresses are not used for any other purpose and are not shared with outside parties.  Acumatica will never willfully release your personal information to any third party unless you direct us to do so or disclosure is required by law.

Acumatica also may collect personal information when you request assistance from our customer support team (e.g., phone number, email address,) and may collect additional information that you choose to share with our customer support team.

Acumatica also collects information to evaluate aggregate site usage.   Acumatica may automatically collect certain usage information from customers, such as Internet Protocol (“IP”) addresses, log files, unique device identifiers, pages viewed, browser type, any links you click on to leave or interact with our services and other usage information collected from cookies and other tracking technologies as noted below. For example, we collect IP addresses to track and aggregate non-personal information, such as using IP addresses to monitor the regions from which users navigate to our Services.  We also collect IP addresses from users when they log into their Acumatica databases as part of our log-in process and for enhanced identity authentication and authorization security.

Acumatica’s services may change over time and we may introduce new features that may collect new or different types of information.

**Cookies**

There is a technology called “cookies” which can be used to provide tailored information from a web site. A cookie is an element of data that a web site can send to your browser, which may then be stored on your system. A “cookie” marks and identifies visitors on an Internet site to allow customers to enter customized information and have it available on subsequent visits. Acumatica pages may use cookies so that Acumatica can provide a customer with access to information when a customer returns to Acumatica’ web site.

Although there has been debate over the privacy implications of cookies, it is important for Acumatica customers to know that cookies do not read your hard drive, nor can cookies be used to reveal new information about you that you have not elected to reveal.  Acumatica may use cookies to log your activity on the site. Everything Acumatica learns from these logs will be used to enrich our users’ experiences on our site. It will help Acumatica understand what you like and don’t like, so Acumatica can focus its energies more effectively and provide you with better service.  Please note that your web browser settings may be adjusted to limit or prohibit this and other websites from placing cookies.

**Security**

Acumatica is committed to protecting the security of your personal information. We use a variety of security technologies and procedures to help protect your personal information from unauthorized access, use, or disclosure. For example, we store the personal information you provide on computer systems with limited access, which are located in controlled facilities.

If a password is used to help protect your accounts and personal information, it is your responsibility to keep your password confidential. Do not share this information with anyone. If you are sharing a computer with anyone you should always choose to log out before leaving a site or service to protect access to your information from subsequent users.

**Connecting or Linking Your Acumatica Database with Third Party Services**

We work with other companies or developers who provide products and services that you may choose to sync, link or otherwise connect with your Acumatica database.  If you choose to make use of such related products or services, we may exchange that information, including your personal information, information from your database, and information about how you interact with each company’s service or product with one or more third parties.  This routine exchange of information is necessary to maintain business operations and to provide the requested services.

**Data Retention**

In accordance with and as permitted by applicable law and regulations, we will retain your information as long as necessary to serve you, to maintain your account for as long as your account is active, or as otherwise needed to operate our business.  Acumatica’s backup policy is set forth on the [Acumatica SaaS FAQ page](https://www.acumatica.com/acumatica-saas-faq/#Backups_1).

When your account expires or becomes disabled, Acumatica may retain the data for up to 30 days before it is permanently removed from all of our systems. We will retain information about our customers as required by applicable regulations and to comply with our legal and reporting obligations, resolve disputes, enforce our agreements, complete any outstanding transactions and for the detection and prevention of fraud.

**Your Access Rights**

You may access your online account to view your personal contact information and make changes or corrections at any time.

Applicable law may give users certain rights to access personal information about them, and to limit use and disclosure of their personal information.  Acumatica is committed to respecting those rights.  If you wish to request access, to limit use, or to limit disclosure, please contact us at [privacy@acumatica.com](mailto:privacy@acumatica.com) and please provide the name of the Acumatica customer who submitted your personal information to our services.  We will refer your requests to that customer, and will support them as needed in responding to your request.

**Communications Preferences and Opt-Out**

As a result of providing your contact information, Acumatica may market to you, including sending promotional communications and relevant offers. To opt out of receiving marketing related communications from Acumatica, please click on the “opt-out” link in the communication. Please note that if you do opt-out of receiving marketing- related emails from us, we may still use your email address to send you important administrative messages. If you wish for us to completely delete your personal record from our database, email [privacy@acumatica.com](mailto:privacy@acumatica.com) and we will delete your contact information. 

**International Data Transfers**

In accordance with and as permitted by applicable law and regulations, we reserve the right to transfer your information, process and store it outside your country of residence to wherever we or our third party service providers operate. ** **

**Changes to This Privacy Statement**

We will occasionally update this privacy statement to reflect changes in our services and customer feedback. When we post changes to this Statement, we will revise the “last updated” date at the top of this statement. If there are material changes to this statement or in how Acumatica will use your personal information, we will notify you either by prominently posting a notice of such changes prior to implementing the change or by directly sending you a notification. We encourage you to periodically review this statement to be informed of how Acumatica is protecting your information.

**Contacting Us**

Acumatica welcomes your comments regarding this privacy statement. If you have questions about this statement or believe that we have not adhered to it, please contact us via email at [privacy@acumatica.com](mailto:privacy@acumatica.com) or by mail at:  Acumatica Privacy, Acumatica, Inc., 11235 SE 6th Street Suite 140, Bellevue WA, 98004

© 2018 Acumatica, Inc. All rights reserved.

Read Acumatica Privacy Policy for Mobile Apps.
